Finding Aid for the Alan Rich Papers, 1960-2010 LSC.1975
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alan Rich papers
1923-2010
1960-2010
UCLA Library Special Collections
Rich, Alan
LSC.1975
12.2 Linear Feet (10 document boxes, 5 record cartons, 7 flat boxes, 2 index card boxes)
Alan Rich was an American music critic, based in New York and Los Angeles, who began his professional career in the 1950s and continued writing until his death in 2010. The collection includes research files, correspondence and memorial tributes, promotional scores and recordings sent to Rich from composers and music publications, an extensive collection of both drafts and periodical clippings of his writings, and recordings from the "Music Room" salons he co-hosted in Los Angeles with philanthropist Betty Freeman.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed digital materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated to UCLA by Alan Rich through the Alan Rich Trust, executed by trustee Raymond Richards and transferred in 2010.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9970150183606533
Biography/History
Alan Rich was born in Boston on June 17, 1924. While attending Harvard in the 1940s, he began working as an assistant music critic for The Boston Herald. Upon graduating, he discarded his original plans to attend medical school and instead enrolled at the University of California, Berkeley. Under the mentorship of the musicologist Joseph Kerman, he earned a master's degree in Music in 1952. After graduating, he went to Europe on fellowship for a year, and then returned to Berkeley to become the music director of Pacifica Radio, station KPFA.
KPFA later sent Rich to New York to work at radio station WBAI; this move led to Rich becoming a music critic for The New York Times in 1961. He moved to The Herald Tribune in 1963, and later wrote for New York magazine from 1968 to 1981. Toward the end of his tenure there he contributed to New West magazine, a spin-off of New York that was soon renamed California. Rich moved to Los Angeles in 1981 and became music editor of Newsweek. He also wrote for The Los Angeles Herald Examiner and LA Weekly. Rich used these national and local publications as a platform for a campaign to put Los Angeles' musical culture in the spotlight. He became a crucial advocate for contemporary music as he continued to make the case for LA's significance as a musical hub throughout his career. Rich's music column was cut from LA Weekly in 2008 as a cost-cutting measure after a sixteen year run. This led Rich to begin a blog, "So I've Heard," named after the title of a 2006 compilation of his reviews, So I've Heard: Notes of a Migratory Music Critic. He also continued to contribute reviews to Bloomberg News, Variety, and others.
Rich was the author of several books, among them Careers and Opportunities in Music (1964), The Lincoln Center Story (1984), American Pioneers: Ives to Cage and Beyond (1995), and the "Play-by-Play" series of books and CDs, with volumes devoted to Bach, Mozart, Beethoven and Tchaikovsky (1995). He passed away in April 2010, at the age of 85.
Scope and Content
The collection includes research files, correspondence and memorial tributes, promotional scores and recordings sent to Rich from composers and music publications, an extensive collection of both drafts and periodical clippings of his writings, and recordings from the "Music Room" salons he co-hosted in Los Angeles with philanthropist Betty Freeman.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in six series:
1. Writings, 1950-2010
2. Subject, 1936-2004
3. Personal, 1932-2010
4. Books, 1923-2008
5. Scores, 1961-2009
6. Media, 1950-2009
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Separated Material
The bulk of Alan Rich's books from his personal library were transferred to the Music Library for individual cataloging. They are available via the UCLA Library Catalog.
Related Material
Related materials providing additional information on philanthropist Betty Freeman, with whom Rich worked closely, can be found in the Betty Freeman Papers (MSS 227) at Mandeville Special Collections Library, UC San Diego.
Music critics -- United States -- Archives.; Rich, Alan -- Archives
- Series 1: Writings, 1950-2010
  Scope and Content
  Series comprises drafts and clippings of Rich's primary publications, including his cover stories for LA Weekly and Newsweek, record and concert reviews, program notes, and radio program transcripts.
  - American Judaism, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - American Pioneers: Manuscript, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - American Record Guide, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Articles: A Publication of California Institute of the Arts, 1980-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cover Stories, 1958-1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Cover Stories, 1991-1997 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Cover Stories, 2001-2004 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Freelance: General, 1970-1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Freelance: Glossies, 1950-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - The Herald Tribune (1 of 4), 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Herald Tribune (2 of 4), 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Herald Tribune (3 of 4), 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The Herald Tribune (4 of 4), 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - History of Music: Manuscript, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - House and Garden: New York Herald Tribune, 1960-1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Houston Grand Opera's An American Voice, Los Angeles Times on the opening of Music Center, and LA Weekly columns., 1964-2000 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - KFAC, Los Angeles, 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - KPFA, Berkeley: Radio Scripts, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - KUSC, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - KUSC, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - KUSC, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - KUSC, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - KUSC (1 of 2), 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - KUSC (2 of 2), 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - LA Weekly: "A Lot of Night Music" Columns, 1992-1995 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - LA Weekly: "A Lot of Night Music" Columns, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - LA Weekly: "A Lot of Night Music" Columns, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - LA Weekly, Life, Herald Tribune, 1990-1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Musical America, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - New York Magazine, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - New York Magazine, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - New York Magazine, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - New York Magazine, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - New York Magazine, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - New York Magazine, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - New York Magazine, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - New York Magazine, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - New York Magazine, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Newsweek: Bach Cover Story, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - The Open Space Magazine, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Program Books, 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Program Notes and Liner Notes, 1980-1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Radio: Music Under Fire, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Radio: Reviews, 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Record Reviews, 1960-1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Reviews and Columns, 1980-1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Romantic Art Song (Radio Program), 1980-1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Piano Spheres: The First Ten Years, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Slonimsky, Nicholas: Interview Transciption (1 of 2), 1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Slonimsky, Nicholas: Interview Transcription (2 of 2), 1992 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - So I've Heard: Manuscript, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - So I've Heard: Manuscript, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - So I've Heard: Volumes 1-2, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Smithsonian, 1984-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Typed Articles, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - West Coast Publications, 1980-1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Series 2: Subject Files, 1936-2004
  This series includes research materials, scripts, and documents pertaining to particular musicians, institutions, or topics. Of particular interest is an extensive interview with musicologist Nicholas Slonimsky, a controversy over coverage of the San Francisco Symphony, and the writings, some unpublished, of composer Robert Erickson, on whom Rich conducted extensive research.
  - Amram, David, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Berio, Luciano, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Brown, Earle, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cage, John: Musicworks, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cage, John: Cage at 80, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cage, John: Cage at 75, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cage, John: Cage's Writing, 1955-1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cage, John: Composition in Retrospect, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Cage, John: Interviews & Recipes, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cage, John: Museum of Contemporary Art Celebrations, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cage, John: University of California, San Diego, Program, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - California Composers Radio Program, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Callas, Maria, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Casals, Pablo, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Casals, Pablo (film), after 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Copland, Aaron, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Criticism, 1970-1999 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - D'Indy, Vincent, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Erickson, Robert: Essays, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Erickson, Robert: Worklist & Correspondence, Criticism, 1980-2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Erickson, Robert: Score, Night Music, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Erickson, Robert: Hearing Things, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Erickson, Robert: Other Worlds, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Erickson, Robert: UCSD Celebration & Writings, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fleishmann, Ernest, 1989-1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Freeman, Betty (1 of 2), 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Freeman, Betty (2 of 2), 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Furtwaengler, Wilhelm, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Giteck, Janice, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Gould, Glenn, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Harris, Roy, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Hartke, Stephen, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Hockney, David, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Hula, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Kerman, Joseph, 1950-1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Kess, Rhonda, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Listening and Silence, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Los Angeles Opera, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1980-1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - New York City Opera, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Piano Spheres, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Pinkham, Daniel, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Public Programs, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Research: General, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco Opera, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - San Francisco Symphony, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco Symphony, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - San Francisco Tape Music Center, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Scherchen, Hermann, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Schubert, Franz: Schubert 10, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Singers: Curtin and Sills, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Slonimsky, Nicholas, 1936-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - So I Hear: Outline, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Stephan, Rudi: Tributes, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Swed, Mark, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Weill, Kurt: Interviews & Notes (1 of 2), 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Weill, Kurt: Interviews & Notes (2 of 2), 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Weill, Kurt: Newsletters, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Weill, Kurt: Research & Sources, 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Weill, Kurt: Rich on Weill, 1982-1998 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Wilson, Robert, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Series 3: Personal, 1932-2010
  The series includes Rich's correspondence with composers, musicians, and publishers, tributes to him (including his festschrift), and reviews of books or projects he created.
  - Awards, Diplomas, Citations, 1932-2009 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1980-2010 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Letters to Editors, 1967-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Play-by-Play CDs, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Poznak, Alan Van, 2000-2009 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Professional, 1980-1999 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Documents and Photos, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dupre, Marcel: Methode d'Orgue, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Festschrift: 80th Birthday, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - LA Weekly: 75th Birthday Tribute, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Tributes, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Notices, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Oral History: KPFA, Berkeley, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Proposals and Contracts, 1980-2002 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Quinn, Janice: Thesis, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Reviews of Rich: Career Opportunities in Music, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Reviews of Rich: CD-ROM, 1990-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Time Capsule (1 of 3), 1950-1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    The time capsule boxes were transferred from a box of the same name, and consist of newspaper clippings by or about Rich from the 1950s and 1960s.
  - Time Capsule (2 of 3), 1950-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Time Capsule (3 of 3), 1950-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - University Work: Research Papers, 1951-1954 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - University Work: Thesis, "Formal Practices in Schubert's Larger Instrumental Works", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series 4: Books, 1923-2008.
  These books cover a broad range of musical topics, from Baroque era aesthetic styles to contemporary musical cultures and communities. Although they represent a small portion of Rich's personal library, many are inscribed to him by their authors or dedicated to him as gifts.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Some books include CDs.
  Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  - Adorno, Theodor W.: Gesammelte Schriften 12, Philosophie Der Neuen Musik., 1975. (Box 2)
    Inscribed to Rich from unknown
  - Amtmann, Willy: Music in Canada, 1600-1800., 1975. (Box 1)
  - Arkatov, James Masters of Music: Great Artists at Work., 1990. (Box 2)
    Photos by Arkatov, with essays by Alan Rich. Inscribed to Rich from Arkatov.
  - Berio, Luciano: Two Interviews., 1985. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Berio
  - Bloch-Morhange, Lise: Vies de Divas., 1990. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Bloch-Morhange
  - Cage, John: Italian Program., 1984. (Box 2)
    Inscribed to Rich from Cage
  - Crawford, John C. and Dorothy L. Crawford: Expressionism in Twentieth-Century Music., 1994. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Crawfords
  - Farneth, David, ed.: Lenya, the Legend: A Pictorial Autobiography., 1998. (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Betty: More Music People: Irvine, CA., 1989. (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Betty: Music People: Carnegie Hall, New York., 2003-2004. (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Betty: Music People: Deutsche Oper Berlin., 1989. (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Betty: Music People: The Photographic Works of Betty Freeman., 1990. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich by Freeman
  - Freeman, Betty: Music People and Others., 1987. (Box 1)
  - Freeman, Betty: Music People and Others: Berlin., 1990. (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Betty: Music People and Others: London., 1996. (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Betty: Music People and Others: Italy., 1987. (Box 2)
  - Garland, Peter: Americas: Essays on American Music and Culture, 1973-1980. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Garland
  - Kerman, Joseph: The Art of Fugue: Bach Fugues for Keyboard, 1715-1750., 2005. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Kerman
  - Kerman, Joseph: Opera and the Morbidity of Music., 2008. (Box 1)
  - Kowalke, Kim H.: Kurt Weill in Europe., 1979. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Kowalke
  - Malm, William P.: Music Cultures of the Pacific, the Near East, and Asia., 1967. (Box 2)
  - May, Thomas, Editor: The John Adams Reader: Essential Writings on an American Composer., 2006. (Box 1)
  - Nayttely, Oopperaa Linnassa: Opera in the Castle., 1997-1998. (Box 2)
  - The Open Space Magazine: Fall 2003, Issue 5. (Box 2)
    Book review by Rich, p. 22
  - Plantamura, Carol: The Opera Lover's Guide To Europe., 1996. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Plantamura
  - Plantamura, Carol: Women Composers., 1983. (Box 2)
  - Reische, Diana: The Performing Arts In America., 1973. (Box 1)
    Contains chapter by Rich
  - Rich, Alan: American Pioneers: Ives to Cage and Beyond., 1995. (Box 2)
  - Rich, Alan: Bach, Cantata 80 and 147. Chinese translation, 1995. (Box 2)
    General
    2 copies.
    Each book includes 1 CD.
  - Rich, Alan: Beethoven: Symphony No. 3 and Egmont Overture. Chinese translation, 1995. (Box 2)
    Includes 1 CD.
  - Rich, Alan: Careers and Opportunities in Music., 1964. (Box 2)
  - Rich, Alan: Johann Sebastian Bach, Cantana No. 147, Jesu, Joy of Man's Desiring., 1995. (Box 2)
  - Rich, Alan: The Lincoln Center Story., 1984. (Box 2)
    Two copies
  - Rich, Alan: Mozart: Piano Concerto No. 20 and No. 21. Chinese translation, 1995. (Box 2)
  - Rich, Alan: So I've Heard: Notes of a Migratory Music Critic., 2006. (Box 2)
    Two copies, unopened plastic wrap
  - Rich, Alan: Tchaikovsky: Symphony No. 5 and Romeo and Juliet Overture. Chinese translation, 1995. (Box 2)
  - Rorem, Ned: Knowing When To Stop (A Memoir)., 1994. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Rorem
  - Rosenfeld, Paul: Musical Chronicle (1917-1923). (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Kermans
  - Schmidgall, Gary: Literature as Opera., 1977. (Box 2)
    Partially corrected proofs
  - Schnabel, Tom: Stolen Moments., 1988. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Schnabel
  - Schonberg, Harold: Facing the Music., 1981. (Box 1)
    Proof. Inscribed to Rich from unknown.
  - Schwendowius, Barbara and Wolfgang Doemling: Johann Sebastian Bach: Life-Times-Influence., 1977. (Box 2)
  - Shapiro, Nat, ed.: An Encyclopedia of Quotations About Music., 1978. (Box 1)
  - Small, Christopher: Music, Society, Education., 1977. (Box 2)
  - Sposato, Jeffrey S.: William Thomas McKinley, A Bio-Bibliography., 1995. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Sposato
  - Surrans, Alain: Jeux de Massacre: 100 compositeurs de A a Z., undated. (Box 2)
  - Wager, Gregg: Symbolism as a Compositional Method in the Works of Karlheinz Stockhausen., 1998. (Box 2)
    Inscribed to Rich from Wager. Possibly a dissertation.
  - Weber, William: The Great Transformation of Musical Taste: Concert Programming from Haydn to Beethoven., 2008. (Box 1)
  - Winter, Robert: Music for our Time., 1992. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Winter
  - Zenck, Claudia Maurer: Ernst Krenek: ein Komponist in Exil., 1980. (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Rich from Krenek
- Series 5: Scores, 1961-2009
  This series includes scores by local and international composers. Some are clearly performance scores, thoroughly marked; some are promotional materials sent to Rich by publishers. Of particular interest is the pre-publication score of John Adams' On the Transmigration of Souls, commissioned by the New York Philharmonic to memorialize September 11, 2001. The completion of Schubert's 10th Symphony is also of interest.
  - Adams, John: Death of Klinghoffer, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Adams, John: On the Transmigration of Souls, Pre-Publication Copy, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Adams, John: The Wound-Dresser, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Carow, Stefan: Five Pieces for Orchestra, Dreams and Nightmares, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Erickson, Robert: Auroras, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Erickson, Robert: Corona, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Erickson, Robert: Down At Piraous, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Erickson, Robert: Ramus, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Harbison, John: Mottetti di Montale, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Kraft, William: Settings from Pierrot Lunaire, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Lear, Evelyn and Thomas Stewart: Edition of Songs, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Inscribed to Rich from Lear and Stewart
  - Lentz, Daniel: Time's Trick, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Leung, Simon: Proposal for The Side of the Mountain, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Lindberg, Magnus: Cello Concerto, 1997-1999 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Marcus, Bunita: Music for Japan, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Previn, Andre: Brief Encounter, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Putt, Alistair: Various, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    With a note from the composer
  - Rorem, Ned: Evidence of Things Not Seen, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Schubert, Franz: Symphony No. 7 in E, Realized by Brian Newbould, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Schubert, Franz: Symphony No. 10 in D Major, Realized by Brian Newbould, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Steiger, Rand: Frame(s), 1998 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Stucky, Steven: Second Concerto for Orchestra, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Subotnick, Morton: All My Hummingbirds Have Alibis, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Subotnick, Morton: and the butterflies begin to sing, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Ten Holt, Simeon: Lemniscaat, 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Unknown Composer: Requiem, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Wilson, Robert: Civil Wars: A Tree is Best Measured When it is Down, Overview, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Series 6: Media, 1950-2009
  This series includes commercial, promotional, and non-commercial recordings of performances, studio recordings, interviews, and lectures. It also includes some video recordings of opera and other performances, reel recordings of various composers work, as well as recordings from the "Music Room" salons Rich co-hosted in Los Angeles with philanthropist Betty Freeman.
  Audio materials in this collection require advance notice for use. Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  - Adams, John: Guide to Strange Places, Promotional CD, 2001 (Box 13)
  - Adams, John: On the Transmigration of Souls, Promotional CD, 2002 (Box 13)
  - Andriessen, Louis: La Passione, Promotional CD, 2002 (Box 13)
  - Arbizu, Ray: Tessabel and Symphony of Love, 45 RPM, undated (Box 20)
  - Belcea Quartet: Bartok String Quartets 1-6. 2 CDs, 2008 (Box 13)
  - Brendel, Alfred: Beethoven Sonatas, No. 27-32. 2 CDs, 1991 (Box 13)
  - California Composers Radio Program (15 Reels), 1980-1981 (Box 22)
  - Chihara, Paul: Minidoka CD, 2008 (Box 13)
  - Chin, Unsuk: Promotional CD, undated (Box 13)
  - Chin, Unsuk: Violin Concerto, Promotional CD, 2001 (Box 13)
  - Del Sol Quartet: Tear CD, 2002 (Box 13)
  - Erickson, Robert: Auroras, 2008 (Box 20)
  - Erickson, Robert: Night Music, 7" Reel, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Glennie, Evelyn: With the Singapore Symphony Orchestra. 1 CD, 2002 (Box 13)
  - The Idaho Falls: Johnny Savant and Mark Wedin. 1 CD., 2004 (Box 13)
  - Kayhan Kalhor and Brooklyn Rider: Silent City CD, 2008 (Box 13)
  - Ligeti, Gyorgy: Interview. 1 CD, 2002 (Box 13)
  - Listening Room with Robert Sherman: Alan Rich, 7" Reel, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Mozart, Magic Flute: Achim Freyer/Salzburg Production. 1 DVD, 1997 (Box 13)
  - Part, Arvo: Symphony No. 4, Los Angeles Philharmonic Live, 2009 (Box 13)
  - Rich, Alan: Composers in California, No. 3 and 4, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Rich, Alan: Interview with Elizabeth Schwarzkopf and Paul Badura-Skoda, 7" Reel, 1973 (Box 20)
  - Schiff, Andras: Lecture. 8 CDs, 2010 (Box 13)
  - Shower Scene From Psycho, 45 RPM, 1984 (Box 20)
  - Stalvey, Dorrance: 5 Compositions. 1 CD, undated (Box 13)